[angry chatter]
-[battle cry]
-Lloyd, look out!
-[gasps]
-[yells]
[shatters]
The medical bots assured us
Lloyd's condition is stable,
but he shows no signs
he will wake up from this coma.
He has to wake up!
We can't do this without him.
Whatever fears he had about
being our Master in the games--
[knock on door]
Oh, I thought Lloyd
would be, uh... Sorry.
We came to do the official
transfer of elemental powers.
Lloyd is technically the victor
of that competition.
But I guess we can wait
until he's... better.
Good news though, we expelled
that pain-in-the-butt Zeatrix!
I can hear you.
And not just
from this tournament,
but from all
future tournaments.
That's it?! After what she did?
Come on, Roby,
you can do better than that.
Or we can do worse.
Listen to me. I-- I was
so caught up in winning,
in proving my worth,
that I blanked out.
I just acted out of rage.
Rage?
[dings]
Was that supposed
to be an apology?
I don't know what your
Caregiver-bot taught you,
but mine always said apologies
should have the words
"I'm sorry" in them.
You know what should be done
to you, Creep-atrix?
You should be... tied up
in front of, like,
a really delicious melon
that you'll never
be able to reach.
No, no, you should be poked
you with a million sticks
while playing songs you hate
on a loop, forever!
Yah.
You don't know who
you're messing with!
♪ Lost in the unknown
So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise! ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
For what's right! ♪
[explosion]
-[growling]
-Stop!
There ' s no fighting
outside the arena!
I keep telling you this!
-[vibrates]
-Ah! Tell that to her!
[zapping]
Sorry, Zeatrix.
Lose your fight,
lose your powers.
Them's the rules!
-[bots warble]
-[screams]
Ah!
I'm sorry about that.
If Lloyd wakes up--
When Lloyd wakes up.
When Lloyd wakes up,
I'll transfer all
the powers to him.
He earned them.
Wyldfyre, you saw Roby was
still wearing those cufflinks
I told you about?
Yeah. They look so fire.
No! I-- I mean, sure,
they are stylish,
but that's not the point.
Those cufflinks have
the same design
that was on the wall
from where
someone sent
those attacker bots.
Roby can't be a suspect.
Did you see how he
just saved me? Us.
Just because
someone acts nice
doesn't mean they aren't
capable of turning on you.
But this is Roby.
What about Zeatrix? Or Ras?
They're way badder!
They're still suspects,
sure,
but the more I think about it,
the more Roby could easily
be behind the attack
on the Matriarch,
and the attacks
on the other players.
I think you're
the wrongest kind of wrong,
but if this means
I get to prove
the stang-zoot
Roby's innocence,
then sign me up.
I can help too, Arin.
Thanks, but no, thanks.
I need Ninja I can trust.
[Arin's Dad]
Remember, Dr. Arin,
when trying to solve a mystery,
trust no one.
Everyone is a suspect
until proven innocent.
Including... you mother!
[chuckles] You got me.
[all laugh]
You sure you don't want
to go to the games plaza
to see Sora fight?
Very sure.
Now's the only time
we know Roby and Bleckt
won't be around their office.
[gasps, grunts]
[buzzing]
We don't have much
time 'til the game is over,
so we gotta hurry.
-[door rattles]
-Well, we tried.
Guess you'll have to trust me
that Roby's innocent.
Would an innocent man
lock his office door?
Yeah. Normal people lock doors.
I was raised by dragons
and even I know that.
Hmm...
[grunts] Ugh!
Lloyd was trying
to teach me Spinjitzu,
but I just don't know
what's holding me back.
There's no chance I'm
making it past the next level
of the tournament without him.
Yah! [sighs]
[Roby]
And for our next match,
she'll wreck you with tech...
you,
and now a bunch of
other cool powers --
Sora!
Versus the Quake Snake
ready to break--
the competition!
Frak!
[crowd cheering]
Something's up with...
What's her name?
Jordana. Yeah.
One minute she's
asking me for help,
the next, she's pretending
she doesn't know me.
Given how I ignored her
when we were in school,
I wouldn't want
to know me either.
Maybe her and Arin
can become friends.
Friends that hate me.
-[grand music]
-[gears cranking]
[Roby] First game today
is a spectacular,
multi-platform fight!
You know the rules:
first to fall, first to lose!
Is everybody ready?!
[crowd cheering]
-[grunting]
-[fireball whooshing]
[both grunt with effort]
Hah!
[grunts] Uh!
[grunts]
[grunts] Hah!
[quietly] Use your balance.
Whoa!
[grunts]
Yah!
Uh!
[rumbles]
-[clangs]
-Aah!
[grunts]
What's someone like you doing
fighting for Ras?
You Ninja got him all wrong!
Sure, he's strict,
but he taught me lots. Hah!
[both straining]
[explosion]
[crowd cheering]
[attack yell]
Whoa!
[crowd cheering]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[Arin] Those masks
will make you more powerful,
but they corrupt you,
poison you.
Ras only cares about power,
no matter what the cost.
Do it! Do not disappoint me!
[clangs]
[snarls]
[both grunting]
-Hiyah!
-Ohh!
Ah!
[grunts]
Yah!
-[crowd cheering]
-Ugh!
Aah!
Ugh.
Sora is the winner!
[crowd cheering]
[whooshes]
[rumbling]
You outplayed me.
Congratulations.
You were a worthy opponent.
-Congratulations, Sora!
-You have more powers, Sora!
You have failed me!
It was a good fight.
A fair fight.
I will not suffer disobedience!
I offered you certain victory,
and you refused!
Ugh.
I never want you
in my sight again.
What? Jordana? Oh, hey.
Huh? An Imperium
math equation?
What does this mean?
[metallic rattling]
Uh--
Hey, heh, I was just
looking for you!
By your office! But of course
you were at the games.
That makes way more sense.
Anyway, I just wanted
to tell you that...
you're funny and cute
and I like that!
And you're a snazzy dresser!
Those cufflinks are fantastic!
Can I see them?
Sure! I think
they're kinda basic, TBH,
but Dad used to wear them
so Uncle Bleckt
thought I should wear them
for my first Tournament.
-Aww.
-Right?
Who'd'a'thought
Bleckt'd be such a softie?
He gave them to me
right before the first game,
like for good luck.
As if I needed it.
[dings]
[bangs]
So, Roby got those cufflinks
right before the first game--
the morning after
the bot attack.
Told ya he was too cool
and good-looking
to have left the mark!
[musical notes]
You have to
trust the evidence, Arin.
Even if it goes against
what you believe.
Even if your Dad is being
a real sneak.
[laughs]
Yeah, you're--
Right! I'm right!
-Feels good! Yeah!
-[door creaks]
[chuckles]
We interrupting something?
Uh, just... feeling good.
Not because of you or anything.
[awkward chuckle]
But not not because of you!
You're great! We're fine!
No big deal! Bye!
[chuckles]
That's the wrong way.
Um... [clears throat]
it was good to see you too,
Wyfy. [clicks tongue]
[squeaks]
And the Elemental Master
of Heat has zero chill.
Why aren't you at the games?
Even if you don't support
your teammates,
have some respect
for the tournament.
[gasps, coughs]
Yeah, good point, okay!
[door creaks]
Bye, now!
Way to go, Sneaky Boots!
[mysterious music]
Detective Arin and Dr. Wyldfyre
are on the case!
-Hmm.
-[boings]
You finding anything?
Nothing.
What were you expecting?
A notebook that says,
"I'm guilty?"
The entrance to a secret lair?
No?
Yes?
And what's this?
[gears cranking]
[gasps] I didn't break it!
You broke it!
Well, well, well!
The entrance to a secret lair!
[chuckles]
For the record,
I'm the one that found it.
It was smart of Bleckt
to hide the room's access
in this old thing.
No way Roby was gonna touch
a rotary phone.
I still don't know
what this is.
[gasps]
Who would do this to
his beautiful, beautiful face?
So, I'm getting the feeling
that Bleckt doesn't like Roby.
That sounds like a motive.
-[pops]
-Ah!
Can we go now?
This room is gonna
give me nightmares forever.
How is this all tied
to the Matriarch horns?
We need evidence.
Is that evidence?
[Arin]
"Meet with Ras."
Sounds like evidence.
But why would Bleckt
meet with Ras
the day before the Tournament?
And if it was a meeting
to commit a crime,
which it obviously was,
why write about it?
He is pretty fussy
with his boring stuff,
like ledgers and rules.
We need more answers.
Arin! I've been waiting
for you.
I need your help deciphering
this note Jordana gave me.
Who's Jordana?
Oh, that girl from Imperium?
Doesn't she hate you?
Something weird is
definitely going on with her.
And this is an Imperium
math problem.
Maybe it's a clue or something?
You're the best
at solving mysteries.
I guess...
I figured out the math...
for all the good it did me.
It spells out the words
"Crown Mono Stereo."
What could that mean?
Crown... mono... stereo...
Crown... uh, hat... head?
Horns? Horns!
Maybe the dragon horns?
Then, mono... one?
Stereo... around... hmm.
Mono... stereo... monostereo...
Monastery?
Horns in the Monastery?
Is Jordana trying to tell me
the dragon horns
are in the Monastery?
Maybe? But why would they be
back in the Monastery?
[Cole]
Not in our Monastery.
I think I know
which one they're in.
But are you sure
we trust what's-her-name?
Not sure we have a choice.
[rumbling]
-[slices]
-[grunts]
[thuds]
[Source Dragon growls]
[fire whooshes]
[whooshes]
[explosion]
Motion Source Dragon...
thank you.
Your visions are from exposure
to Source Dragon Energy.
I can ward them off,
but they will be back.
Being a Conduit, as you are,
is a grave responsibility.
And a responsibility
I have failed.
I've lost in the Tournament.
A Source Dragon like myself
would not have come to you
if I did not believe
you could do this.
But we still haven't discovered
who's behind the attack
on the Arc Dragons,
or who's threatening you.
Which is exactly why
you must get back
in the games,
no matter what.
Lloyd, you must win!
[gasps, panting]
[gears cranking]
Good afternoon, everybody!
[cheering]
"Woo" is right!
The next game
is gonna be a spicy one.
First up, he's mysterious and
his handshakes really hurt:
Nokt!
Versus... he's lean, green,
and definitely not mean:
Lloyd!
[crowd murmuring]
What is Roby trying to pull?
He knows Lloyd
is still in a coma.
[sighs]
The Tournament must go on.
[crowd murmurs]
[sighs]
With Lloyd not attending,
I'm afraid I must
call the fight.
And the victory goes to--
Lloyd!
[crowd cheering]
Lloyd! Come on, Lloyd!
You can do it!
-Woo-woo-woo!
-Yes!
Where are we go--
whoa...
Looks like the orb that led me
here has made some friends.
If you're right about
the Imperium girl's clue,
this has gotta be the place.
But how are we gonna
get over there?
Our dragons were sent home.
And you don't have your
Elemental Powers anymore
-to make a bridge.
-Thanks for the reminder.
And Sora's too busy fighting
to help us out
by building us a ship
or something.
Hey, I could come up
with a million ideas
that won't work, too, like...
Okay, I'm bad at improv
but let's focus on trying
to come up with a plan
that might work. Like-- ooh!
I've got an idea!
Wait right here.
Okay...
-[flames whoosh]
-[upbeat music]
What an unexpected comeback!
Lloyd is back
in the Tournament!
[cheering]
This is so much cooler than
anything I could've planned.
I'm not even mad you wouldn't
let me use killer jellyfish
anymore.
Lloyd! I'm so glad you're here,
but you sure
you should be here?
I can still fight. I have to.
And here are the powers
that are rightfully yours!
[zaps]
[dings]
Lloyd, look out!
[grunting]
Yah!
Ah... [grunts]
-[grunts]
-Ah!
-[zaps]
-[grunts]
[grunts]
Uhn!
Ah!
[cheering]
[thuds]
[Source Dragon]
Lloyd, you must win!
[Lloyd grunts]
[attack yell]
Ugh! [panting]
[grunts]
-[dings]
-Stop the fight!
[crowd gasps]
[panting] What?! Why?
You are clearly
an injured combatant!
According to ancient rulings,
the Source Dragons,
in their desire for fairness,
do not permit injured fighters.
Oh. Wow.
Well, if it's in the rule book,
I guess...
But you saw me.
I could do it!
I'm just a little sore,
no big deal!
I...
I don't have a choice, Lloyd.
Even though that match
was awesome!
Your health is
the most important thing.
You did not look well
this morning,
and you still don't,
to be honest. Sorry.
And victor by default is...
Nokt!
[gasps]
[mysterious music]
Well, hello there.
[zaps]
I'm glad you're awake, Lloyd.
I hope... I hope
you'll be okay.
The odds were not
in our favor.
You did your best.
It wasn't good enough.
I've failed us.
I've failed all of us!
No, you haven't.
I'm still in the games,
I just need you to train me.
[thuds]
Cole, is that you?
But that's
an elemental earth mech,
you don't have your powers.
How can you get it to work?
I'm pretty sure this mech
was my mother's.
I can feel something in it,
some connection.
So, maybe if I focus...
[powers up]
[thuds]
[rumbling]
[grunts]
All right! Let's go!
[mysterious music]
[Cole]
Master Wu?
[closing theme playing]